Miscellaneous Benjamin Franklin Collections 1710-1822 Mss.B.F85.misc
American Philosophical Society
- Jane Mecom Collection, 1728-1789; Mss.B.F85.m; 65 items
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1773 Nov. 1; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1774 March 23; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1774 July 28; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1774 Sept. 3; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to [Jane] Mecom, 1774 Sept. 26; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed in part: Symth, v.6, 246.
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1775 Feb. 26; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Jane Mecom, 1775 June 17; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to [Jane] Mecom, 1775 Aug. 2; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to [Jane] Mecom, 1775 Oct. 16; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to [Jane] Mecom, 1776 Dec. 8; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to [Jane] Mecom, 1777 Oct. 5; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to [Jane] Mecom (sic), 1779 April 22; L.S. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to [Jane] Mecom (sic), 1779 Oct. 25; L.S. 4p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to [Jane] Mecom, 1784 June 17; A.L. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Jane Mecom, 1785 July 13; L. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, v.9,363.
  - to Jane Mecom, 1785 Oct. 1; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to [Jane] Mecom, 1785 Oct. 27, 29; ALS, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Jane Mecom, 1786 Jan. 1; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1786 Jan. 24; ALS, 4p. and 3 end. - 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Bigelow, v.9,283; Petition in Smyth,v.5,550.
  - The petition of the letter Z..., A.D. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth,v.5,530 (does not include the marginalia.)
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1786 June 3; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, v.9,514.
  - to Jane Mecom, 1786 July 4; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, v.9,522.
  - to Jane Mecom, 1786 Sept. 21; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, v.9,539.
  - to [Jane] Mecom, 1789 Feb. 22; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1789 Aug. 3; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, v.10,33.
  - to Jane Mecom, 1789 Dec. 17; L. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed in part: Smyth, v.10,73.
  - to [Benjamin Franklin], 1773 Dec. 9; ALS, 1p.; Shipley, Jonathan
  - to [Benjamin Franklin], [1774?] Jan. 12; ALS, 3p.; Shipley, Jonathan
  - to [Benjamin] Franklin, [ca. 1773]; ALS, 3p.; Shipley, Georgiana, d.1806
  - to [Benjamin Franklin], [ca.1773]; ALS, 1p.; Shipley, Jonathan
  - The chiding [verses], D. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to his sister [Sally Franklin], 17[61] Oct. 10; L. 2p; Franklin, William
- Ledgers and accounts of Benjamin Franklin's legacy to the city of Philadelphia., 1791-1870; Mss.B.F85.ledgers; 4.0 Volume(s) 757 p.
  These four volumes include an account ledger (1791-1870), a bond account ledger (1791-1861), and two bond books (1791-1826), relating to the administration of Franklin's bequest to the city of Philadelphia of a fund to provide financial aid to young married artificers.
  Presented by Philadelphia Mayor Joseph Clark, 1954.
  - Dr. Franklin's Legacy Bond Book No. 1, 1792-1828; 1.0 Volume(s)
  - Dr. Franklin's Legacy Bond Book No. 2, 1819-1836; 1.0 Volume(s)
  - Dr. Franklin's Legacy Account Ledger, 1791-1870; 1.0 Volume(s)
  - Dr. Franklin's Legacy Bond-Account Ledger, 1791-1868; 1.0 Volume(s)
- Diplomas, 1753-1786; Mss.B.F85.di
  Presentesd by Charles B. and Mary Fox
  - Accademia di Scienze, Lettere, ed Arti di Padova, 1781
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1781
  - Bataasch Genootschap der Procfondervinderlyke Wysbegeerte Rotterdam, 1771
  - City of Edinburgh [Scotland], 1759
  - Harvard University, 1753
  - Royal Medical Society, 1787
  - Royal Medical Society of Paris, 1777
  - St. Andrews University, 1759
  - St. Andrews University [Latin], 1759
  - Societá Patriotica di Milano, 1786
- Address of Earl of Macclesfield to Royal Society, 1753; Mss.B.F85.m3
  Original manuscript of the address declaring the designation of Sir Godfrey Copley's Medal to Benjamin Franklin.
  Presented by A.D. Bache, 1882
- Photostats of Franklin papers not held at APS, Mss.B.F85.pd
  Photostats of microfilm copies of Franklin papers not held by APS. They are arranged chronologically.